# **Albert Duro**

Web Developer

## Contact

**Address** 

Warri, Delta, 332281

**Phone** 

234-706-30699

E-mail

duro.slyvester@gmail.com

**Twitter** 

https://twitter.com/durosly\_

LinkedIn

www.linkedin.com/in/durosly

**WWW** 

https://zety.com/profile/albert-duro/161

## **Skills**

Website optimization

Web development projects

**JavaScript** 

CSS

Search Engine Optimization

HTML

Project Management

Programming

Web Security

Solution-driven Web developer capable of contributing to a highly collaborative work environment, determining customer satisfaction, and finding solutions. Proven experience using Nextjs to create consumer-focused websites. Over the course of four years, created products for desktop and mobile app users that met the highest standards for web design, user experience, best practices, and speed. Designed and built web applications using a variety of APIs, third-party integrations, and databases.

## **Work History**

#### 2021-07 -Current

#### **President of Student Union**

National Association Of Computer Science Students, Warri, Delta

- Kept institution financially sound by tracking expenses and maintaining detailed records.
- Conferred with educators to identify current classroom concerns and diversify instructional strategies.
- Strengthened programming operations by aligning processes to capitalize on new educational trends.
- Optimized student educational strategies with clear advice on course choices, progression and career options.
- Managed over 5 association leaders and over 200 students.

## 2020-08 -2020-11

## **Web Developer**

swiftransact, Warri, Delta

- Established presentation consistency across Chrome, Safari, Firefox and other common browser interfaces.
- Wrote lines of code using HTML, CSS, JavaScript and PHP.
- Oversaw back-end development using PHP to maintain website integrity, security and efficiency.
- Adhered to SEO best practices while designing sites.
- Increased reach by 10% and sales by 4%.

## **Education**

ReactJS	
NodeJS and Express	
NextJS	

TailwindCSS

2017-02 -	Bachelor of Science: Computer Science
Current	Federal University of Petroleum Resources, Effurun - Ugbomro, Effurun, Delta State
2014-02 - 2015-02	Associate of Science: Marine Engineering Assitant
	Joe Marine Institute Of Nautical Science - Airport Road, Effurun, Delta State
2005-09 -	High School Diploma
2011-09	Army Day Junior And Senior Secondary School - Effurun Refinary Road

## **Hobbies**

I enjoy reading as well as teaching others. I love coding, travelling, solving puzzle, playing chess and video games.